

# Pham Thi Hai Yen

Date of birth : June 10<sup>th</sup>, 1991

Place of birth : Dak Lak

Mobile phone : 0349 668 569

Email : haiyen167080@gmail.com

#### CAREER OBJECTIVE

With more than 9 years of experience in the field of Human Resources, taking on different functional roles of the HR&ADM Department, I am aware of the core value of Human Resources Management in the development of each organization, towards the goal of becoming an excellent and dedicated HR Manager, bringing the highest quality and best Human Resources service to all employees and the entire organization.

#### EDUCATION

- Bachelor of Finance and Banking, University of Economics Ho Chi Minh City (2009 2013)
- Master of Finance and Banking, University of Economics Ho Chi Minh City (2015 2018)
- TOEIC 850 (IIG Viet Nam)

## EXPERIENCE RECORD

#### ROHTO MENTHOLATUM (VIETNAM) LTD. COMPANY

Sep 2019 - Present

# Senior HR Development & Total Reward Specialist

# Main duties:

- Assist HR&ADM Director in designing, planning, and implementing benefits, wellness, and compensation programs, HR policies and procedures ... ensure that total rewards initiatives and HR management programs are aligned with the strategic direction of the Company, legal compliance and cost effectiveness.
- Assist HR&ADM Director in monitoring all HR related activities including recruitment, compensation & benefits, career development, performance evaluation, training and development, employee engagement...

#### • Total rewards and C&B

- Design and implement comprehensive C&B plans that are aligned with the Company's business objectives and talent management strategies.
- Annually review and update C&B Policies, ensure salary bands and rewards structure are fair and competitive with the external market.
- Review and update HR policies/procedures based on Company's expectation, ensure high compliance with local Labor Law, advise management on needed actions.
- Develop and promote the solid HR management system that ensure the accuracy, transparency and fairness in talent management and development, including Career development roadmap, KPI & OKR evaluation, Competency framework, Training Path...
- Build and annually update the performance assessment method applied to different levels and grades, conduct performance evaluation training and guide employees on how to apply the new evaluation system effectively.
- Communicate and advise new methods/ solutions to assess and evaluate employee performance, identify gaps, and create strategies from those analyses to cultivate talent and improve performance at all levels of the Company.
- Maintain work structure by updating job requirements and job descriptions for all positions.

- Advise Board of Director and Department Heads in regard to key business and HR management issues.
- Forecast & control HR budget.

#### • Training & Development

- Closely work with Heads of department & HRBP to identify and analyze the training needs; build the training plans based on job requirements and business's needs as well as building the training development roadmap for promoted employees/succession team.
- Build an excellent Trainers team and Train-The-Trainer team to deliver the best service of internal training.
- Liaise with external training agencies to deliver efficient training services for employees in a cost-effective manner.
- Apply KPI to measure the performance of external training agencies, enhance the quality of training service deliverer by third party.
- Conduct the training quality survey, analyze the collected data to propose appropriate solutions to improve the training quality of professional skills, soft skills, and leadership skills.
- Compose and review the training materials.
- Take the role of Trainer in some programs of HR Department: Performance evaluation training, Induction training, Soft skills training...
- Control and manage the training cost effectiveness.

#### • Recruitment

- Develop comprehensive strategic talent acquisition and retention plans that meet the business's human capital needs.
- Build and develop the recruitment process, SOP and recruitment standards, such as designing the entry test (IQ/EQ Test, Professional knowledge test), developing the competencies-based questionnaires and interview skills... ensure hiring right person-right position and at the right time.
- Advise Recruitment team on activities of employer branding, enhance the techniques and skills of talent sourcing/profile screening and interviewing, ensure the productivity and working efficiency.
- Closely work with Heads of department to identify and forecast the personnel needs, execute the employment plans as needed.

#### • Employee Engagement

- Assist HR&ADM Director in designing and implementing engagement initiatives and programs in order to strengthen organizational solidarity, support enhancing core values, branding and HR engagement, such as: Caring Fund, Sharing Fair, Community Workshop, English Club, Recognition Culture...
- In charge of Company's HR engagement activities: Happy Hour, Birthday, Mid-Autumn, Christmas, Year-End Party, Company Trip...
- Prepare the contents, concepts for each program; creatively design and develop PR activities & communication plans; smoothly and creatively organize the programs that highly satisfy all of participants.
- Deliver a best HR service to all employees as soon as they start working as a new comer, create a culture of "One team".
- Design and implement the annual Organizational Health Index survey, analyze the collected data to propose appropriate solutions in order to improve the wellbeing, health and performance of the Company.

#### FAR EASTERN POLYTEX (VIETNAM) LTD. COMPANY

Sep 2018 - Jun 2019

Position: HR Generalist cum Assistant to Vice President

Main Duties: Assist Vice President and HR Director in studying and developing the Competency Framework applying to all functional Departments of the Company; build and develop competency-based training plan, competency-based interview skills which are applicable for whole Company.

#### • Project Management

- Lead the Project Team to study and develop the Competency dictionary and Competency framework for the Company.
- Work closely with all Department Heads to discuss and develop Competency Framework in align with their practical functions and direct how to apply Competency effectively to employee's assessment/appraisal.

- Interview and make a survey to exploit employees' performance, strength and weakness; find the gap to propose appropriate solutions, develop practical training and developmental programs.
- Conduct the training for all relating departments and employees on how to apply the Competency effectively.
- Work with training & recruitment team to build competency-based training plan and competency-based interview questionnaires.

#### • Recruitment

- Keep close contact with the universities in HCM city to build and develop potential candidate resources through employment branding, job fair, potential internship opportunity,...
- Compose and update Job Description for each functional position, post job advertisement through many popular recruiting channels
- In charge of recruitment process: sourcing and screen suitable CVs, arrange interview, welcome & on-board process...; build up and develop Talent pool (candidate database) to support effectively recruiting activities.
- Make recruitment planning and take good care of all recruitment activities, ensure that qualified candidates are recruited timely to meet the needs of department.

# • Training & Development

- Identify and analyze the training needs, develop and implement training plan, evaluate the quality and effectiveness after training.
- Build the specific and suitable training models for each group in the Company
- Collect, build and develop the suitable training programs
- Advise Board of Directors on solutions to improve the quality of training activities in the Company
- In charge of trainer role and composing training materials in terms of Company culture/policy and understanding Labor Law/Social Insurance Law to all employees.

# • Employee Relation

- Communicate matters of compensation and benefits to employees.
- Solve personal problem of employees including reward and discipline, performance appraisal

# BANK FOR INVESTMENT & DEVELOPMENT OF VIETNAM (BIDV)

Sep 2013 - Jul 2018

# Position: HR Supervisor

Main Duties: Assist HR&ADM Manager in implementing general HR management & administration activities, including: C&B, Recruitment, Training & Development, Employee Relation, Administration...

#### • Compensation and Benefit

- Responsibility for monthly payroll (salary, allowances, deductions, adjustments, over time, sick leave...) for employees, ensure payment monthly salary on time and confidential.
- Manage social insurance, medical insurance, ensure compliance with Vietnam insurance Law.
- Manage all matters related to social insurance and employment related documentation.
- Prepare all data for the annual salary review and annual performance appraisal analysis.
- Communicate matters of compensation and benefits to employees.
- Solve personal problem of employees including reward and discipline.
- Set up and maintain HR policies, including recruitment, training, compensation and benefit policies for employees.
- Measure employee satisfaction and identify areas that require improvement.
- Follow-up and update Labor Code and related legal regulation. Regularly revise Company policy if needed.

#### • Recruitment

- Make recruitment planning and take care all recruitment activities, ensure that qualified candidates are recruited timely to meet the needs of department.

- Develop and implement recruitment strategies, process and programs to ensure the hiring of the best qualified employees for the Company.
- Ensure the selection and the hiring decision process to be carried out in a professional manner and with quality and timing.
- In charge of recruitment process: posting Job ad, Source and screen suitable CVs, arrange interview, welcome & on-board process...

# • Training

- Identify and analyze the training needs, develop training plan, implement training plan and evaluate the effectiveness after training
- Build the specific and suitable training models for each group in the Company
- Diversify the training methods to be suitable for each employee in the Company system.
- Develop and standardize the internal trainers in all areas of the Company operations
- Advise the Board of Directors on solutions to improve the quality of training activities in the Company

#### • Administration

- Manage and take care of office maintenance services.
- Follow up, purchase and maintain the food and beverage in office, keep them available all the time.
- Managing the filing, storage and security of documents as well as preparing documents and reports per assignments.
- Follow and check sanitation worker to keep the office cleanly.
- Manage and organize all Company activities and events, such as Company trip, establishment anniversary, team building activities, year-end party... build the contents, concept, scripts and take the role of Host or MC.

# Planning

- Prepare HR reports and statistics monthly.
- Set up, maintain and consult to Director about HR Policies, including recruitment, training, compensation and benefit policies for employees.
- Consult and cooperate with functional department to restructure and optimize Organization Structure, setup KPI for employees.
- Plan and implement all activities for Training and Development by internal or external.
- Frequently study feedback of working condition and environment from staff to consult with HR Manager, Director.
- Measure employee satisfaction and identify areas that require improvement.

#### SKILLS

- Fluent in Vietnamese, English
- Proficient in Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint...)
- Strong ability of data analysis & excel, logical and critical thinking to interpret complex data and make sound decisions.
- Experience in performance assessment, project leading and working with multiple stakeholders, able to handle multi-task.
- Highly energetic, self-motivated, independent and results driven.
- Able to work accurately and efficiently under high pressure.
- Strong leadership skills, risk management and change management capabilities.
- Strong presentation skills, communication and influencing skills.